(Wind blowing)
(Distant bird calls)
(Wings flapping)
(Sparse, intriguing piano)
(Hens clucking)
(Sheep bleating)
Here.
(Pigs grunting)
(Boy sighs)
(Boy grunting)
(Honking)
-(Distant clatter)
-Huh?
(Moving music)
(Whoosh)
(Heavy breathing)
(Wheel creaking)
(Whooshing)
(Chimes)
Arco!
ARCO:
Ugh, another plant?
What'd you think we were
bringing back?
-A dinosaur?
-Did you see any?
-GIRL: A mother triceratops.
-Whoa!
She was huge! She would
call her babies like this:
Rarrr!
WOMAN: And that's where Ada
found the fern,
or else we probably
wouldn't have noticed it.
-Did you pet them?
-GIRL: Pet them?
Are you kidding?
We were way too scared.
We hid.
(Whispering) Dad was terrified.
Exactly what I thought,
Dryopteris.
With that, we'll be able
to grow thousands.
Dad? You think
that next time I can go along?
Arco,
we've already discussed that.
-You're too young.
-But if I come, I could help.
Yeah, right, the only thing
he's interested in
-is seeing dinos.
-DAD: Ada.
She's right though,
we don't travel for fun.
ARCO:
But I told you I'm ready.
No flying before the age of 12.
It's the law.
That's the way it is.
Your time will come.
Don't be in such a hurry.
(Wind blowing)
(Tense music)
(Chimes)
(Sharp inhale)
(Sucking in air)
(Distant, lone bird call)
(Floor lightly creaking)
(Crickets chirping)
(Grunt)
(Wind gusting)
(Momentous music)
(Chimes)
-(Music fades)
-(Deep breath)
(Heavy breathing)
(Panicked breathing)
(Harrowing music)
(Whimpers)
(Shouting)
(Muffled shouting)
(Gasping for air)
-(Uplifting music)
-(Grunting)
-(Chimes)
-(Shouts)
(Laughter)
Woohoo! Woo!
(Shouting)
(Static)
(Music fades)
(Thunder pealing)
("Sunshine, Lollipops,
and Rainbows" by Leslie Gore)
♪ Sunshine, lollipops,
And rainbows ♪
♪ Everything that's wonderful
Is what I feel ♪
♪ When we're together ♪
♪ Brighter than a lucky penny ♪
♪ When you're near the rain goes
Disappears, dear ♪
♪ And I feel so fine ♪
♪ Just to know
That you are mine ♪
♪ My life is sunshine,
Lollipops, and rainbows ♪
♪ That's how this refrain goes ♪
♪ So, come on,
Join in, everybody ♪
♪ Sunshine, lollipops,
And rainbows ♪
♪ Everything that's wonderful
Is sure to come your way ♪
♪ When you're in love to stay ♪
-(Music stops)
-(Baby giggling)
-VOICE WITHOUT: Are you ready?
-Yes! Yeah!
Now we have our new hats.
Shh!
VOICE: I heard there were
some newcomers out west,
two of the toughest outlaws,
especially the girl,
who goes by the name
of Calamity Jane
with nails as sharp
as an old pair of talons.
All of the sheriffs out there
are looking for her,
but I'll be the one to find her!
(Baby laughing)
Who do you want now?
Do Hook! Hook!
Hook! Hook! Hook!
(Inner machinery whirring)
(Thunder peal without)
(Baby crying)
It was just lightning, Peter.
Don't worry, our house
is protected from the storm.
(Robot imitating train noises)
GIRL: He won't listen
to anyone these days.
-All he wants is his way.
-MOM: That's normal.
At his age, you were a holy
terror too, wasn't she, Mikki?
A real monster,
if I remember correctly.
Go on, sweetheart. Eat your
purée, be good. Do it for Mommy.
And how was school today?
MOM: How did your history
presentation go?
-OK.
-(Peter whimpering)
I mean,
Clifford was so terrified
that he forgot the whole part
about the pharaohs.
He was shaking like a leaf,
like this.
(All laugh)
Oh, Mikki,
you got the appointment
-for Peter's vaccine's, right?
-MIKKI: Yes,
I'm bringing him in
for his boosters tomorrow
and I went shopping
for Saturday.
Iris is making
a lemon meringue pie.
Mikki! It was a surprise.
MIKKI: Oops. My bad.
Actually, about that...
we can't come home this weekend,
we have too much work.
But... what about your birthday?
DAD:
Hm, we'll celebrate next time.
MOM: We'll try to come
next weekend. OK, baby?
MOM: "'I'm youth, I'm joy!'
Peter answered at a venture.
This of course was foolishness,
but it was proof
to the unhappy Captain Hook
that Peter did not know
in the least who he was
or what he was.
(Yawn)
Which is the very pinnacle
of good form."
And then?
I have to get up early.
- Turn off the light soon, OK?
-Yes, Mommy.
I love you so much.
(Smooch)
-Goodnight, angel.
-(Digital trilling)
-Night, Mama.
-(Zap)
(Thunder peals without)
(Thunder)
(Clattering)
(Static buzzing)
(Knock at door)
(Door opens)
-(Soft music)
-Everything all right?
I can't sleep.
Make a little room for me, OK?
Tell me what's wrong.
Nothing, I said.
I'm fine.
I'm sure they would prefer
to be with you
instead of the office.
When you're a grown-up, you
can't always do what you want.
Do you think
wishes really come true?
Like in fairy tales?
I don't know, Iris.
But what's to stop you
from trying?
(Music fades)
(Thud)
-(Machinery whirring)
-(Birds chirping)
(Intriguing music)
(Vehicle back-up alarm)
-(Doorbell rings)
-(Footsteps approach)
(Peter squeals)
-Hi, Mikki!
- Good morning, young man.
-Late again, huh?
-Iris!
-Clifford's here.
-Coming!
-You're going to be late!
-I said I'm coming!
(Birds chirping)
-(Iris giggles)
- Be careful on the road,
-you hear?
- Yes, Mikki!
-CLIFFORD: Bye bye!
-(Peter murmurs)
Hurry up!
Why do you always get
to drive?
-'Cause it's my scooter.
- Iris!
I said to drive carefully!
Ugh, your sister
is as stubborn as a mule.
CLIFFORD: Isn't that
Mr. Deschmaker's car?
Oh, yeah, it is.
He's gonna flip out.
IRIS: Where do you think
birds hide during a storm?
I don't know,
I've never thought about it.
I used to wish
that I could be a bird
to be able to fly and be free.
Actually, it must be horrible.
I would want to be a cat:
nothing to do,
you walk around, they feed you.
Cats have it all figured out.
IRIS: But I don't like cats
because they eat birds.
CLIFFORD: Did you see
on the news about the fire?
My dad says this time
it's gonna destroy everything.
IRIS: He says that
every time, Clifford.
We have enough canned goods
to last for months.
-Where are you putting it all?
-In the living room,
in my bedroom, I'm sleeping
-on the red beans.
-Haha!
-See you at lunch?
-Yup, see you later.
(Children clamoring)
(Bell rings)
PROF: The universe,
like all living things,
was born one day.
That day occurred
13.8 billion years ago
in a massive flash of light
we call the Big Bang.
Prior to that instant,
time and space did not exist.
At birth, the universe weighed
just 20 micrograms,
the weight of a grain of sand.
That is an average
of 7.7 pounds less than you
when you were born,
and then like you it grew,
forming galaxies and
our solar system. Yes, miss?
I don't feel well.
May I be excused, please?
We only have 15 minutes left.
-(Tense music)
-I have a headache.
All right, go on then.
Thank you.
Right, let's continue.
Four and a half
billion years ago...
(Music stops)
(Hovercraft passes)
(Pattering)
Hm?
(Intriguing music)
(Chimes)
(Gasp)
(Heavy breathing)
(Music fades)
(Bird wings fluttering)
(Tense music)
(Bird cawing)
-(Rustling)
-(Boy shouts)
(Iris gasps)
(Arco groaning)
(Sigh)
Are you all right?
That was some fall.
-Did you break anything?
-Whoa...
(Thud)
Hey!
(Gasp)
Who are you?
MAN 1:
Where are we going?
MAN 2: You're talking too loud,
everyone can hear you.
You're unbelievable!
-MAN 1: What?
-MAN 2: I'm picking this up.
-It's beeping like crazy.
-Let me see!
-Look, it's beeping.
-MAN 3: I got it too!
-Holy smokes!
-MAN 1: We need to split up.
-All right? Dougie!
-Yeah?
-You go North.
-All right.
And Frankie and me,
we'll go South.
Wait, hold on a second.
Really?
-Why am I the...
-It's not all about you!
DOUGIE: It's not all about me,
you're crazy.
You go off on your own
over there
-and the two of us will...
-(Branch snaps)
-ALL: Huh?
-(Tense music)
ALL: Oh!
Shh!
(Whispering)
What do I do? What do I do?
(Men grunting)
(Shouting)
Ah! You're so heavy!
(Grunts and shouts)
-Ah, hello, sirs.
-Whoa!
-(Thud)
-(Shouts)
IRIS: Are... are you looking
for the treasure too?
What?!
I mean, I just saw a rainbow.
Don't you know
about the legend?
At the end of the rainbow,
the pots of gold and...
Listen, sweetie,
we're busy, go away.
DOUGIE: Don't be so rude,
Frankie, come on!
-Come on!
-Sorry.
Um, little girl, have...
have you seen anything strange
in the woods?
No.
STEWIE:
Are you sure?
I mean, uh...
there was that little boy.
ALL: Little boy?!
-(Sigh)
-IRIS: That's right.
-He ran off that way.
-(Laughter)
You can't miss him
with his weird outfit.
-Oh!
-It's incredible!
Was he in a bright costume
with a cape? A cape?
IRIS: Yeah, with lots of colors.
You think he's looking
for the treasure too?
It has to be him,
you just heard what she said.
A kid with a cape!
Let's go. Hurry up.
Uh, goodbye. Thanks, miss.
-Come on, no time!
-Thanks so much, madam.
DOUGIE: Now what's the plan?
STEWIE: Here's the plan,
Dougie and me'll go North.
FRANKIE: No! I said already
I do not want to!
(Argument fades)
(Mysterious music)
(Heavy breathing)
(Shudder)
(Grunting)
(Tense music)
-(Wind rushing)
(Music fades)
-(Faucet running)
-(Iris sighs)
Mikki!
I was starting
to get seriously worried.
Can you help me please?
(Sigh)
He was really out of it,
then all of a sudden, boom!
-He fainted!
- We have to treat it right away
or else he'll be left
with a very bad scar.
Go get me the first-aid kit,
would you, please?
-Where is it?
- In the bathroom upstairs,
top drawer under the sink.
He's fine, no serious injuries,
just that small boo-boo.
Can I have that?
Let's get to work then.
I think he'll need
at least eight stitches.
-(Robot machinery whirring)
-Ugh!
That's gross!
-(Phone ringing)
-(Chopping within)
They're not picking up.
MIKKI:
They must be busy at work.
Would you set the table, please?
-IRIS: Think he's a leprechaun?
- I don't really think
they exist, Iris.
What could he be then?
Did you see his cape?
No idea,
but what I understand even less
is what you were doing
all by yourself in the woods.
I already told you.
I saw a rainbow.
Iris, I know
you're bored in class,
but you can't just leave school
like that.
Isn't a little boy who falls
from the sky important?
Little boys don't fall
from the sky.
I think he must be a wizard.
Or maybe an angel.
You can ask him about it
when he wakes up.
(Tense music)
STEWIE: We've been going
in circles for three hours.
-This is useless!
-FRANKIE: I don't understand.
The signal is weaker now,
but the machine says it's here.
STEWIE: Your machine's
never worked, Dougie.
It's trash. I give up.
FRANKIE: She was kinda weird,
the little girl.
DOUGIE: We might as well
face reality, huh?
We've been wasting our time
for 20 years.
STEWIE: Huh? Hey, guys!
-FRANKIE: Yeah?
-DOUGIE: What?
-STEWIE: Look at that.
-Ah!
-DOUGIE: What... what is it?
FRANKIE: I don't know, but
I don't think it's from here.
(Peaceful music)
(Mom murmurs)
Arco?
DAD: What's going on?
Arco?!
(Heavy breathing)
DAD AND SISTER: Arco?
No, no, no! No!
Arco!
(Voice ringing out)
(Arco murmurs)
(Shudders)
IRIS: You all right?
Do you remember me
from the woods?
What's your name?
Mine's Iris.
Um, what year is it?
IRIS: Well...
it's 2075.
(Chuckle)
My parents are gonna kill me.
IRIS: Where are you from?
(Gasp)
My flying suit! Where is it?
In the machine.
The what?
-IRIS: The washing machine.
-Give it back!
-Now!
-OK, OK.
Wait for me here,
I'll be right back.
(Distant music box playing)
(Music grows louder)
ARCO: Huh?
(Robot machinery whirring)
(Arco gasps)
(Static buzzing)
-(Gasp)
-(Soft zap)
(Gasp)
Oh, wow!
(Washing-machine whirring)
Huh?
-You had eight stitches.
-(Shrieking)
MIKKI:
They'll gradually dissolve.
Calm down.
It won't hurt you. It's Mikki.
It took care of you.
What's your name?
Arco.
Arco what?
Arco Dorell.
You don't exist.
- You don't...
-But Mikki, he's right here.
(Mikki indistinct sputtering)
Mikki,
what's the matter with you?
(Sputtering)
Mikki, are you there?
(Power-down)
Whoa, you made it crash.
Is it dead?
Of course not.
Robots don't die.
(Knocking)
Come on, Mikki.
Restart.
ARCO: Well, it looks dead.
Come on, help me put it
on the sofa.
(Grunts)
-It's heavy!
-I know.
(Wincing)
It's an old model.
What kind of robot do you have?
Uh, um...
You don't have a robot?
How do you manage?
Who cleans up after you,
does the laundry, makes meals?
Well, we do.
So, where are you from?
(Commotion without)
-(Doorbell rings)
-(Gasp)
It's the insurance bots.
They can't see you.
Hide in here
and don't move a muscle.
ARCO:
But... but I can't stay here!
-IRIS: OK! OK!
-ARCO: I have to leave!
IRIS: Don't fly away.
Good morning, miss.
We've been alerted to a bug
affecting your nanny bot Mikki,
serial number 28976.
Is that correct?
Yeah, that's right.
It's in the living room.
Can you describe to us
precisely what happened?
Uh, I don't know yet,
it just started to say nonsense.
There have been many errors
in the region,
312 exactly,
because of the storm.
-How long have you had it?
-Forever.
Do you think it's serious?
My coworker will now implement
the standard check-up.
It should only take
a few minutes.
May I?
I think we have a 404.
IRIS: Is it bad?
No need to worry,
it should be reparable.
Do you know
how long it will take?
It's impossible to say.
Our service has been overbooked
since yesterday.
(Gasp)
Oh, no.
No, no, no!
(Dog barking far off)
-(Back-up alarm)
-(Thud within)
(Whoosh)
(Moving music)
(Gasp)
(Heavy breathing)
(Birds chirping)
(Bird whistle)
IRIS: Do you understand
what they're saying?
(Arco chuckles)
ARCO: They're saying
you're a good person.
They're usually hard on us.
(Gutter clangs)
-(Music fades)
-(Arco grunts)
Iris, my diamond,
give it back to me.
-What?
-ARCO: There was a diamond
on my flying suit.
I didn't see a diamond.
Maybe you lost it
when you fell in the woods?
Then let's go back there
right now.
OK, but tell me
where you're from.
-I can't.
- No problem.
-Good luck then.
-Wait!
I can't go home without it.
Too bad.
(Scoffs)
That's not cool!
ARCO: Please, please, please!
Hear that, Peter?
He wants to go home?
My parents will start
to worry.
I'm a little busy here.
Someone just broke my robot.
-Hold on, wait, wait!
-(Peter babbles)
You win.
I'll tell you.
Well, um...
I'm from the future.
I thought
there'd only be robots, that...
we'd all become machines
or something.
-There are still humans?
-Well, yeah.
What's it like? Go on, tell!
Are the ice caps melted?
Are there still koalas?
Oh, I love koalas,
they're so cute,
but apparently
they're nasty to each other.
Uh, can we please go now?
Yeah, no problem.
But, uh, not in that outfit.
(Touching music)
What are those poles
with wires going everywhere?
IRIS: They bring electricity
to our homes.
You don't have them?
No, our houses
are self-sufficient.
What do you mean?
They can make their own energy.
And the little boxes there,
what are those?
Guess.
Bird feeders?
No, not that.
-They're mailboxes.
-"Mailboxes"?
IRIS:
They're for receiving messages,
but we don't use them anymore.
You only really get bad news
in them.
ARCO: And... your parents?
-Are they dead?
-Huh? No, not at all.
They work in the city
and come back on the weekends.
Huh? Wow, you're so lucky.
My parents are always
on my back.
My father's always going,
(Annoying voice)
"Don't do this, Arco.
Don't do that, Arco."
(Bird squawking)
ARCO: You sure
this is where you found me?
IRIS: Well, yeah!
What does it look like exactly?
ARCO:
Like a big glass candy.
IRIS: How big?
About this big.
And what's this big diamond do?
ARCO: It diffracts lights.
Without it, we can't travel
through time.
Don't you have a back-up
just in case?
-(Peter babbles)
-Or a plan B?
Um, well,
it'd have to be raining
and sunny at the same time,
but that's very rare.
It's all over, I'm so dead.
(Sigh)
Hold on a sec.
-I have an idea.
-(Peter murmurs)
(Motors whirring)
(Horns honking)
(PA jingle)
PA: Attention, shoppers,
we'd like to remind
our loyal customers
that the limit is
five identical items per person.
Once again, five identical items
per person.
-(PA jingle)
-ARCO: (Whispered) Wow!
CLIFFORD: Hey!
Iris!
IRIS:
Oh... hey.
Are you here
to pick up supplies?
Did you see the news?
They're saying
we'll be totally stuck
at home soon.
Clifford, meet me at check-out.
Yes, Dad, coming.
Uh...
Clifford, this is Arco.
My...
cousin!
Arco, Clifford's a friend
-from school.
-Hi, Arco.
ARCO: Hm...
IRIS: When someone holds out
their hand, you shake it.
It's the polite thing to do.
Otherwise people start thinking
you're weird
and will start
asking you questions
and you don't want people
asking you questions.
(Hover shopping cart whirring)
Ah, this is exactly
what we need.
FRANKIE: I've never seen
anything like it.
Yeah, well,
it could also just be some piece
of plastic jewelry
the kid dropped.
Shut up, Stewie,
you wouldn't know the difference
between a shard of glass
and an emerald.
-Ah!
-(Stewie groans)
Am I bothering you, Dougie?
You made me lose my place.
What will you do
with that stuff?
DOUGIE: House cleaning,
you ever hear of that?
Do you even know that word?
It's a real pigsty inside.
You never put stuff away.
You let everything pile up,
I can't stand it!
-Huh?
-(Bickering continues)
(Arco indistinct)
(Stewie gasps)
-Hey, you guys!
-DOUGIE: What?
It's the little girl
from the woods.
Go get me the Oxybul.
Oh, right!
Yeah, wait, uh...
-Sorry, the what?
-The sound amplifier!
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Right, right.
-(Clattering)
-(Dougie mumbling)
I, I, I...
Oh, got it. I got it!
(Chuckling)
Oh, oh, OK.
-I'm getting no sound here.
-(Tweaking)
-(Blare)
-(All shout)
-My ear!
-Hold on, I gotta adjust volume.
(Whispered)
What are they saying?
I can't really hear.
The baby's crying,
but I think they're talking
about the baby bottle.
-FRANKIE: Great, that helps!
-Shh!
Shh!
(Babbles)
It's incredible how calm he is
with you.
With Mikki he's just so fussy.
(Ambient birdsong)
(Iris soft grunt)
Your sandwich.
It's my favorite.
Hm?
-Do you like it?
-Mhm!
I was really starving.
It's amazing how different
everything is.
IRIS:
What's it like in your time?
ARCO:
Almost everything is underwater.
The sea has risen a lot
since the Great Fallow.
-IRIS: The Great Fallow?
-(Intriguing music)
ARCO: When we moved to higher
ground to let the Earth rest.
Now we live in the clouds.
The houses are built
on platforms
and anchored to big pillars,
sort of... like giant trees.
Wait a sec.
(Clicks pen)
(Iris mumbling)
Kind of like this?
Yes, except our houses
are round.
My sister says
that we live in turtle shells.
And with huge gardens.
STEWIE: Ah, there's static!
I can't hear!
FRANKIE:
What are they saying?
They're talking
about treehouses.
-What?
-Ah...
What? The fallow?
-The Fallow.
-Fal-what?
-It's fallow. Fallow.
-What's that?
-Like this?
-Wow.
It looks just like home.
You draw super well.
-Can I keep it.
-I'll make you a better one.
(Sigh)
I really wish I could draw.
You can express
whatever comes into your mind.
I wish I was able
to talk to birds.
Oh, that's easy!
Anyone can do it.
-Can you teach me?
-What bird do you want?
I don't know.
-Blackbird.
-That's the hardest one.
IRIS: Then a dove.
(Dove call)
-IRIS: You're teasing me.
-No, I'm not! (Chuckle)
-IRIS: What'd you say then?
-I said...
I like you.
(Touching music)
(Imitates call)
(Laughter) You said something
not very nice.
-Oh, yeah? What'd I say?
-No, no!
I can't repeat it.
It's too gross. (Chuckle)
(Dove call)
(Repeats call)
-(Laughing)
-(Imitating call)
No! No, no!
(Imitating call)
(Both laugh)
-So, what are they saying?
-Sweet nothings
in bird language.
-(Frankie sighs)
-Huh?
Tell me something in sparrow.
(Sparrow call)
(Deep inhale)
OK, I'm not even gonna try.
(Laughter)
-(Laughter fades)
-(Iris sighs)
IRIS: Let's go?
(All clamor)
Hey, guys! They're moving!
-(Dougie grunts)
-(Clatter)
DOUGIE: Ah! Argh!
(Grunting and shouting)
-Ow! Push!
-Hey, get a move on! Hurry up!
You want help?
-No, no, I got it. Don't worry.
-(Stewie clamoring)
STEWIE: Go! Go! Go!
FRANKIE:
I'm going as fast as I can!
DOUGIE: Start the van! Start!
-(Screeching rubber)
-(All scream)
STEWIE: No! The other side!
No, that way! That way!
(Birds chirping)
-(Peter murmuring)
-(Mobile chiming)
(Peter giggles)
Here we go.
I've emptied the house.
I didn't know
we had this many pillows.
I'll try it out.
(Grunt)
It works!
(Wind blowing)
(Soft piano music)
There, this should work.
Hm.
(Babbles)
IRIS: OK.
Well... here goes.
(Grunts)
IRIS:
Just in case it works.
(Soft murmur)
We have to say goodbye then.
All right. Go.
Let's do it.
FRANKIE: Did you see that
outfit? It's exactly the same.
STEWIE: Hey!
FRANKIE: I told you
that little girl was weird.
But they're so sweet together!
Not what we're here for.
Go get the camera!
Why is it always me
who has to do the stupid stuff?
-Hey, seriously?
-OK, I'll do what I have to.
-They're going to hear us.
-Oh, oh, I'm sorry!
-Shh!
-(Crank)
-(Water hissing)
(Bubbling)
(Intriguing music)
(Sprinkler hissing)
(Grunt)
IRIS: Ready?
Mhm!
IRIS: On three, you jump.
One...
two...
three!
(Arco shouts)
-(Whoosh)
-ARCO: Ah!
(Arco grunting)
(Blows raspberry)
Arco! Are you OK?
-Woohoo! Perfect!
-(Cheers)
-That's wonderful!
-We have our proof!
-Wonderful!
-(Laughter)
I forgot to press record.
-What?!
-No way!
-I'm really, really sorry.
-No!
It was wild, there were
rainbow sparks everywhere.
I felt too heavy.
It'll never work.
IRIS: Yes, it will.
It's like when I saw you
in the sky.
There was a big trail
behind you.
You need more momentum.
You should jump from the roof.
(Grunting)
The same as before?
ARCO: OK!
(Tense music)
(Grunting)
IRIS: Hey, Arco!
You ready?
ARCO: Yeah, I'm ready!
IRIS: OK!
One...
two...
three!
(Grunt)
(Wind blowing)
-(Whooshing)
-(Arco grunts)
-(Iris gasps)
-(Arco shouting)
-(Ping)
-(Music fades)
(Explosion)
(Wind hurling)
(Wind fades)
Woohoo! It worked!
(Sad music)
Arco?
DOUGIE: I don't believe it.
You filmed the tree.
You filmed the flora.
You big dummy!
I always told you I didn't know
how to use this stupid thing!
You know what? I'm outta here.
I'm outta here!
See you guys later, sayonara,
auf wiedersehen, ciao !
I give up!
-(Peter crying)
-(Sprinkler dying)
(Sad music continues)
IRIS: Everything's fine, Peter.
Everything's fine.
He flew away, that's all.
(Peter moaning)
Yeah, in the sky.
Just like that, poof!
I wish he could have stayed
a little bit longer too.
I'm silly.
I should have asked him
more questions.
(Doorbell rings)
Hey, hey, Calamity Jane!
My Mikki! Ah!
(Iris laughing)
I have so many things
to tell you! (Grunt)
I wish my life had been normal.
At least now we know
we're not crazy.
But that's not the problem.
It's what other people think.
We're a laughing stock.
Blegh, we're gonna have to go
back and live with Mom and Pop.
I'd like to forget
the whole thing.
-(Blast)
-(Men clamoring)
-(Arco shouting)
-(Peter giggles)
(Gasp)
Arco!
-Arco!
-(Arco whimpering in pain)
Your cape...
There's not enough light.
MIKKI: This is private property,
young man.
But Mikki, remember?
This is Arco.
(Peter murmuring)
Arco what?
(Dog barking far off)
(Inaudible)
(Whirring)
CLIFFORD: Huh...
What's going on?
IRIS:
You never believe me!
MOM: Iris, don't speak
to your parents that way.
IRIS: You're such a tattle tale!
MOM: Don't take it out on Mikki,
that's not fair.
MIKKI:
I searched in every archive
and he's nowhere to be found.
It's as if he didn't exist.
DAD: Well, we're gonna have
to call the police.
- I don't see any other way.
-No!
Dad, please! Please!
We can't tell anyone.
But Iris,
think about his parents.
They must be worried to death.
We have to tell them
- we found him.
-That's just it.
you can't tell them.
That's the whole problem!
Well, sweetheart,
you have to explain why.
Swear you'll believe me?
DAD:
Of course we'll believe you.
Promise?
-Swear it!
- Iris, please.
(Sigh) There's no way
to contact his parents
'cause, um, technically...
they don't exist yet.
-They're from the future.
- OK, that's enough.
You've got to stop making up
stories for attention.
You see? You never believe me!
I'm sick of it!
And you're never around anyway!
-Liars! Liars, liars, liars!
- Iris...
DAD: If there's one thing
I can't stand, it's lying.
MOM: Don't you think you took it
a bit too far?
DAD: No, I'm sorry.
We're still her parents.
-(Iris snivels)
-MOM: Well, what do we do now?
DAD: I don't think
we have a choice.
Mikki, call the police.
MIKKI: I'll take care of it.
(Iris whimpers)
We can't stay here!
The police are coming!
FRANKIE: We should sneak in when
they're asleep, snatch the kid,
then we can ask him
all the questions
-we want.
-You must be nuts.
You're unbelievable!
No, we're not criminals.
We should go ring
the doorbell now.
We say we're coming
from Child Welfare
and ask to speak with the kid.
The robot will open the door,
moron.
Your story won't last
two minutes.
-(Iris grunts)
-Are you all right?
(Heavy breathing)
Huh?
-(Thud)
-(All shout within)
-Huh?
-What was that?
(All exclaim in disbelief)
I don't believe it,
they're getting away!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
-Right, hurry up! Gotta move!
-Now!
(Motor approaching)
(Tense music)
-ARCO: Where are we going?
-IRIS: To my school.
(Dogs barking far off)
Stop!
(Distant sirens)
We'll go through the woods.
Follow me!
Shoot! They've gone off road!
DOUGIE:
Triple shoot! The police!
Listen, stay calm.
Whatever happens, don't say
a word. Leave it to me.
I'm gonna throw them
off the scent.
ROBOT: Gentlemen,
where are you going, please?
(Coughing)
Uh...
We got an emergency call.
We're doctors.
May I see your identification,
please?
Ah, yes, my license, of course.
-Uh, I know I have it somewhere.
-(Frankie and Stewie groaning)
DOUGIE: All right, listen,
I haven't got it on me,
but I, um... It's an emergency.
-All right?
-(Whispered) Dougie!
They're getting away!
This is an emergency, OK?
MIKKI: Iris?
The police are here.
Iris?
(Peter babbles)
Iris!
POLICE ROBOT:
You can't go outside.
The Bubble Plan is underway.
STEWIE: Listen, officer,
do you really want the life
of a child on your conscience?
Every minute that passes
could be fatal.
-We're nanosurgeons!
-FRANKIE: No, neurosurgeons!
-Nano or neuro?
-Nano!
-You are a child killer!
-(Screeching)
-What are you doing?
-(Shouting)
(Suspenseful music)
(Men shouting within)
DOUGIE:
Why did I crash through them?
'Cause you don't know
how to lie!
DOUGIE:
I do too know how to lie!
Oh, yeah? And you think
we look like doctors?
No!
(Coughing)
Yes!
(Music softens)
(Distant sirens blaring)
IRIS:
I've never been here at night.
I don't recognize anything.
-(Birds squawking)
-(Gasp)
(Cawing)
What are they saying?
(Branch snaps)
Run.
Run away.
-(Tense music)
-MOM: Mikki, what's going on?
DAD: Hello? Can you hear us?
MIKKI: Iris ran away
with the boy.
I have her GPS location.
- I'm on her trail.
- She's only ten, Mikki.
There're fires everywhere. You'd
better hurry up and find her.
-MOM: We're on our way.
-DAD: Keep us updated.
(Peter babbling)
(Sirens blaring past)
(Rubber screeching)
Argh, we'll never be able
to ditch them like this.
You got a better idea?
You want to drive?
Why do you take everything
so personally?
Brake! Quick, turn right!
Argh!
(Shouting within)
(Thudding)
(Horn beeps)
(Music softens)
-(Heavy footfalls)
-IRIS: Huh?
(Children heavy breathing)
(Clifford gasps)
(Whimper)
-(Rocks sliding)
-(Grunt)
(Tense music builds)
(Men shouting within)
-(Slam)
-(Engine dies)
(Groaning)
(Dougie laughing)
We lost them, we lost them.
Never been so scared, ha!
-Look at that, you guys!
-Huh?
(Exclaiming and laughing)
DOUGIE: Wow, wow, wow!
Whoa, whoa!
Haha!
-(Wind blowing)
-(Tense music)
(Grunting)
-(Doors clattering)
-(Men grunting)
-DOUGIE: Hurry up, guys!
-STEWIE: OK, we're coming!
-Relax!
-FRANKIE: All I do is hurry!
(Shouting)
(Stewie coughing and moaning)
(Sirens approaching)
Hm?
(Indistinct news report
on TV)
-(Whispered) Don't make a peep.
-Hm.
TV: The mayors of
neighboring towns have agreed
to send reinforcements
of personnel and equipment.
And I've just been told
that two ten-year-old children
went missing this evening
in the Elmwood neighborhood.
Anyone with information,
please contact the authorities.
-(Whispered) Come!
-(Grunt)
TV: Do not intervene.
-(Clatter within)
-Huh?
Anyone there?
(Grunts)
(Whispered)
Iris.
(Gasp)
Don't worry,
they're in sleep mode.
This is the teachers lounge.
Hm.
(Clatter without)
(Footsteps approaching)
(Deep breaths)
(Soft gasp)
(Nervous exhale)
-(Smack)
-(Grunt)
(Thud)
-(Click)
-STEWIE: Well, well, well.
You really gave us a hard time,
kids.
Don't be scared.
-We don't want to hurt you.
-(Tense music)
We just wanna know
what the rainbows are.
DOUGIE: Twenty years ago,
we saw someone
just like you, kid.
FRANKIE: Nobody believed us,
not even our parents.
The doctor said it was
a collective hallucination.
-(Chuckling)
-DOUGIE: We lost hope.
And then you arrived
-in the same outfit.
-(Gasp)
The same cape,
the same diamond
on your forehead.
-How do you know
about the diamond?
-IRIS: No, Arco!
-And that's...
why you can't go home,
isn't it?
(Peter muffled giggling)
ROBOT: Chief, Unit 12 called.
We have a problem.
Unknown individuals
have infiltrated
the interior of the school.
I'm responsible for two children
who are inside.
I have to go in.
Let it through.
We can't go in there.
We are going
to activate the units on site.
-(Menacing music)
-Huh?
(All gasp)
-(Haunting music)
-(Beeps)
ALL: What are you doing
on school property?
Stay right where you are.
If they catch you,
they'll never let you go home.
You're gonna have to run fast.
FRANKIE:
OK, kids, on three.
STEWIE: One...
Two! Ah!
(Clanging)
(Heavy breathing)
(Whimpering)
(Shouting)
Cliff! What are you doing here?
CLIFFORD:
I thought you were in danger.
You're the one who did this?
(Clifford shouting)
FRANKIE: Tell us the truth, kid!
-DOUGIE: Are there a lot of you?
STEWIE:
Does the government know?
FRANKIE:
Where do you come from?
STEWIE:
From another planet!
I'm sure that you come
from another planet.
-You're aliens!
-That way!
DOUGIE:
You are aliens, aren't you?
FRANKIE: Think about it, Dougie.
If he was an alien,
he wouldn't speak our language.
STEWIE:
Ah, you're from Atlantis, right?
ARCO:
I just come from the future.
MEN: From the future?
(Exclaiming)
FRANKIE:
I was right all along! Ha!
-(Dinosaur growling)
-Whoa!
FRANKIE: You owe me
a bottle of champagne!
Woohoo!
-(Door creaks)
-Haha!
STEWIE: We're heroes, guys!
We're heroes!
I have an idea.
We'll hide in the library.
-No one ever goes there.
-Go! Go! Go!
We gotta move! We gotta move!
Hup, hup, hup! Go on!
Go, go, go!
Go on! Get in! Hurry, hurry!
-(Crank)
-Wait, wait for me!
-STEWIE: Get a move on!
-DOUGIE: I'm coming!
-Haha!
-Go!
-(Music fades)
-(Coughing and gasping)
CLIFFORD:
I knew he wasn't your cousin.
-(Crowd clamoring)
-(Horses whinny)
Nothing in Room 315.
(Squelching sounds)
-(Seamen shouting)
-(Swords rasping)
Nothing in the 312 either.
Wait, wait, wait!
So, you can travel
to any time period?
I would go to ancient Greece
or to see the Mayans.
I bet life is sweet
with the Mayans.
The Incas. Sorry,
he gets everything confused.
-Oh, give me a break!
-Guys, stop.
Arco, why have you come
to our time?
This period...
isn't it the worst
of humanity, huh?
Uh...
actually...
uh, it was a mistake.
I didn't really choose.
DOUGIE:
Did I say something wrong?
Iris, here.
-(Chimes)
-Go give it to him.
(Mysterious music)
(Soft gasp)
Hm.
STEWIE:
(Whispering) Hey, kid...
are you a little bit in love?
Ew! No way!
Don't worry about it, Clifford.
Don't worry about it.
I once loved a girl too.
But I never had the courage
to tell her.
CLIFFORD:
What happened?
Nothing.
You know,
when you truly love someone,
no matter if they love you back,
the most important thing
is making them happy.
(Alarm blaring without)
Here.
(Gasp)
Now you can go home.
Thank you.
They're not so bad after all.
-Hey there!
-Ahem!
We're here too!
We're not moving!
I guess this time...
it's really over?
(Snivels)
(Sob)
What's wrong?
ARCO: I'm gonna miss you.
(Snivel)
I hate saying goodbyes.
What if I go with you?
That's impossible.
But why?
No one should know the future.
Ever.
-(Thud without)
-(Gasp)
-What's that?
-Huh?
-The bubble, it's closing up.
-(Suspenseful music)
DOUGIE: Quick! Hurry up!
STEWIE:
Go! Go! Go!
For the fallow land!
(Stewie grunting without)
(Air gusting)
(Short of breath)
FRANKIE: This is crazy.
They'll never give up.
Go on, Arco!
Wait, Dougie.
(Door slams)
CLIFFORD:
What do we do now?
-(Arco grunting)
-IRIS: Wait!
(Momentous music)
Arco, wait!
Arco!
Whoa, whoa!
I wanna come with you!
ARCO:
You can't, Iris.
I'm so sorry. You can't.
Arco! Arco, please!
(Sobbing)
Don't leave me alone!
Don't abandon me.
It's too high!
I can't make it.
I'll give you a leg up, Iris.
But Clifford...
(Pounding at the door)
Do what I tell you!
(Clang)
(Iris shouts)
-(Suction sound)
-(Thud)
(Sighs)
MIKKI: You can see for yourself
they're in danger.
-(Digital trilling)
- Let me through!
- Prohibited. Prohibited.
- Look, they're in danger!
- According to safety protocol.
- Iris!
- Let me through!
- Stop, halt right there!
- Iris!
- Halt right there!
(Peter muffled squealing)
(Feet screeching on glass)
(Arco groaning)
(Both shout)
-(Whoosh)
-(Moving music)
(Shouting past)
(Iris gasps)
ARCO:
We're too heavy! I can't steer!
(Grunt)
We have to go higher!
(Both shouting)
(Tense music)
(Chimes)
(Majestic music)
(Grunting)
-(Music stops)
-(Both gasp)
-(Cape whipping)
-(Suspenseful music)
(Gasps and grunting)
(Crows cawing)
(Birds screeching)
(Moving music)
(Peter muffled giggling)
(Bird yelping)
(Giggling)
(Crying)
(Whirring)
-(Great crash)
-(Music fades)
(Cries echoing)
(Calmly breathing)
(Slow breathing)
(Gasp)
-(Drilling sound)
-(Arco murmurs)
Mikki?
(Gasp)
(Soft music)
(Approaching footfalls)
Mikki?
(Distorted)
Huh?
(Gasp)
(Sputtering)
Mikki, what's wrong with you?
MIKKI: (Glitching)
Ir... is.
Memory... disappearing.
(Powering down)
IRIS: (Choked up)
Mikki, what happened to you?
MIKKI:
Mem... ory.
Mikki...
(Glitching)
leave.
No, please.
Mikki...
Ir... is.
-No!
- Leave...
IRIS:
I'm begging you!
(Power-down)
(Sob)
Wake up.
Come back.
(Sobbing)
Come back!
Please.
(Music fades)
-(Click)
-(Whirring)
(Footsteps fade)
IRIS: Arco, wake up.
Huh?
(Peter murmurs)
ARCO
Peter?
We have to leave.
Where are we?
No idea.
(Gasp)
ARCO: Oh, no.
(Soft groan)
Wait, I'll help you.
IRIS: Just trying to figure out
how to turn it on.
(Metal wincing)
-(Click)
-(System turning over)
-Ah!
-(Engine powering)
(Rails screeching)
(Gasp)
Look.
(Metal wincing)
(Bugs chirping)
(Peter murmurs)
(Bird screech echoes)
(Bird screech)
ARCO: An owl!
-IRIS: What's it doing here?
-It found a way out!
(Grunting)
IRIS: Faster!
ARCO: You feel it?
There's wind!
(Owl screech echoing)
(Thud)
(Heavy breathing)
(Bugs chirping)
(Frogs croaking)
(Owl screeches)
(Intriguing music)
(Croaking)
Oh, hey! We're down here!
(Both shouting)
-We're down here! Right here!
-Hey!
(Music fades)
ARCO:
We're... We're right... here.
-We're right here.
-(Gasp)
Your cape.
Oh, no!
No, no, no...
(Arco sighs)
I've wrecked everything.
All I wanted to do
was to see the dinosaurs.
IRIS: I don't understand.
ARCO:
Children aren't allowed to fly,
not till they're 12.
IRIS:
But the flying suit,
the diamond, the cape.
ARCO:
They're my sister's.
(Mysterious music)
Know what?
Before you arrived,
I made a wish.
ARCO:
Don't tell it to me
or it'll never come true.
IRIS:
In a way...
it already has come true.
Of course it didn't happen
exactly how I wanted,
but...
I think that one way or another,
both of us are responsible.
(Pattering)
(Chimes)
(Peter murmurs)
-Look!
-(Gasp)
(Majestic music)
Wow!
(Peter murmurs)
(Incoming whirring sound)
(Whoosh)
(Peter exclaims)
(Gasp)
(Music softens)
WOMAN:
Arco!
Arco! Arco!
My little Arco!
(Sigh)
OLDER WOMAN: Arco!
But...
Arco! My love!
I am so happy to find you,
so very happy!
ARCO: Mommy?
Daddy?
(Choked up)
What happened to everyone?
We searched everywhere
for years.
(Whimpering)
No...
We traveled all through time
-looking for you.
-No.
ARCO:
But you... you...
(Sob)
DAD: Don't be sad.
We've found you.
-(Whimper)
-Everything's all right.
I'm so very sorry.
I'm so sorry.
(Touching music)
(Air gusting)
MOM:
Hello, young lady.
What's your name?
-Iris.
-(Peter murmurs)
And this is Peter.
Can you say hello, Peter?
Hello, Peter.
Thank you so much.
Without you, we would have
never found our son.
IRIS:
But I don't understand.
The drawings
in the cave.
We must go back.
ARCO: (Hesitating)
What are you going to do?
How will you get back home?
Don't worry.
It'll be OK.
(Peck)
Thanks for everything.
IRIS:
Don't forget me.
Never.
DAD: Arco.
(Music builds)
ARCO:
You didn't tell me.
What was your wish?
I wanted things to change.
(Air gusting)
(Music fades)
(Peter murmurs)
(Pensive piano music)
♪ Like flowers ♪
♪ Floating in the sky ♪
♪ Your sorrow flies away ♪
♪ The watercolor in your eyes ♪
♪ Will paint a brighter day ♪
♪ What will you find? ♪
♪ Along the light? ♪
♪ It feels
Like you're clouds away ♪
♪ Together again ♪
♪ Like sun and the rain ♪
♪ Let's call it a brighter day ♪
(Vocalizing)
(Bird chirping)
(Music builds)
(Vocalizing)
(Music continues)
(Music fades)
(Ambient birdsong)
(Music box playing)